You done? - Yes. Almost.
- 好了吗? -马上来
Hurry up. Hurry up.
快点，快点
Today we'll reach early and take the front row.
今天我们早点到，坐前排
After so long I've completed the DPP.
我终于做完了DPP试卷
Batla sir is right.
巴特拉先生说得对
If one knows inorganic the questions get solved instantly. - Yes.
无机物学的好，没有问题解不了 -是的
Lord knows why they teach SPDF orbital.
天知道他们为什么教原子轨道
They should begin with Inorganic.
就应该从无机物开始
That ways student's confidence will get a boost. - Yes.
这样学生的自信心一定能够得到提升 -是的
For the first time I could finish the DPP in fifteen mins.
这是我第一次在15分钟内做完DPP
I finished in twelve.
我十二分钟就做完了
Well, it's possible you made some mistakes in haste.
有可能没有仔细读题
Wait for it to be discussed. - Really?
- 走着瞧 - 真的吗？
Well, alright. We shall see.
好吧，我们走着瞧
The one who has more correct answers..
分数低的人
..has to treat the other to Shreeji's onion puffs.
要请对方吃泡芙
It's a bet. - It's a bet.
那就来赌一把
You will lose. - Come. Come. Come.
-你会输的 -快走吧
You have to do something. It took you 15 minutes.
你应该加快速度了，这题用了你15分钟
One should take time but do it perfectly.
花点时间没问题，但要做得完美
Vaibhav Pandey!
瓦伊巴夫潘迪！
Yes, aunty.
是的，阿姨
Vaibhav Pandey. - Yes, aunty.
瓦伊巴夫潘迪-什么事？
Your fan was left on yesterday. - No, aunty. The fan was off.
你的风扇昨天没关-不，阿姨，风扇关了
It was on! - Maybe it was left on.
没关! -也许是你没关
Aunty, the fan was off. - Don't tell lies.
阿姨，风扇关了-不要说谎
I could hear the fan on full speed all the way up.
我能听到风扇的声音
Aunty, when the sound of our fan can't be heard our room. - Yes.
阿姨，在我们的房间听不到风扇的声音 -嗯
How can the sound of our fan be heard in your room?
在你的房间里怎么可能听到声音？
Don't apply your physics in this matter..
别跟我说你那些物理学理论
..because if the fan is left on again..
如果你晚上再不关空调
..I shall apply my math and increase 200 rupees in the rent next month.
我就用我的数学理论，给你下个月的房租涨200卢比
Bunty!
邦蒂！
Aunty. List..
阿姨……
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
走，走，走
Old hag! She is demanding money whilst brushing her teeth.
老巫婆! 她一边刷牙还要一边要钱
So give her the money. - It's not about the money.
那就把钱给她-这不是钱的问题
Lalita Pawar!
拉里塔 · 帕瓦尔！
In dad's presence she was acting like Nirupa Roy.
在我爸面前，她表现得像妮露帕 · 罗伊
He is like my Bunty.
"他就像我的儿子"
I like.. Damn!
"我喜欢..." 该死！
Even if I have to sleep with the fan off..
即使我不得不关着风扇睡觉
..I won't give her an excuse to increase the rent.
我也绝不会给她涨房租的借口
Okay. You can think about Tarka later.
好吧，先别想这个了
Let's sit in the first bench now and show them.
我们去前排抢个位置，让他们看看
Only ten minutes left in class.
还剩10分钟下课
Everybody pay attention.
大家注意了
This is a very important exception.
这是一个非常重要的例外
It was asked in JEE 2005.
这是 JEE 2005年真题
Silver Iodide is an ionic compound still it's not soluble in water.
碘化银是离子化合物，但它不溶于水
Why? Because Fajan's rule applies here.
为什么? 因为这适用于法杨原则
What was it? - No ionic compound is completely ionic..
什么是法杨原则?-没有离子化合物是完全离子的
..and no covalent compound is completely covalent.
没有一种共价化合物是完全共价的
Very good!
非常好！
Right, Meenal. You see..
是的，米娜尔，你看
Just like that your rank just rose by 500
就这样你的排名就上升了500
and you move from Computer Science in IIT BHU to Metallurgy IIT Bombay.
从印度理工的计算机科学转向孟买冶金学
Look, its Inorganic that improves rank.
看到了吧，无机物可以帮你提高排名
What was your rank, sir?
你的排名是多少，先生？
What? DPP.
什么?DPP？
Yes, yes. Let's do DPP.
好的，那让我们来看 DPP
All of you bring it out. Come on.
你们都拿出来，快点
Get this repaired.
把这个修好
This is most important. - Yes, sir.
有一件很重要的事情 -是的，先生
Please continue.
请讲
These are the faculty feedback forms.
这是教师反馈表
Fill if you care to and return them in two days.
两天之内填好交上来
And only five days remain towards the third installment.
另外距离第三期付款只剩下五天了
And the next lecture will also be given by Batla.... sir.
下一堂课也将由巴特拉主讲，先生
As you might be knowing Bansal sir has gone to Romania for the Math Olympiad.
班萨尔先生已经去罗马尼亚参加数学奥林匹克了
Abroad? - Yes.
- 国外?-是的
And you. Get a haircut.
还有你，去理个发
Where are you loitering?
你是哪个班的？
Yes. So, let's do the DPP. - Yes, sir!
好了，我们看一下DPP吧 -好的，先生！
Good! I like excited state.
很好! 我喜欢兴奋状态
Good!
很好！
Yes. So, the first answer is A.
第一题答案是A
The second answer is C.
第二题C
The third answer is D.
第三题D
The fourth answer is
第四题答案是
B.
B
The sixth answer is C.
第六题答案是C
C.
C
Now write your marks on the DPP.
现在把你的分数写在试卷上
And keep them away for revision.
然后把它们保存好以后复习
And what about the 15th, sir.
15题是怎么回事，先生
That is a chocolate problem.
那是额外的奖励题
I included that exclusively for the A1 batch. You skip it.
这题是给A1的学生出的，你可以不用看
Okay, sir. - Sir! Sir!
好的，先生 -等下，先生
Sir, how can the answer to the 14th question be C?
先生，第14个问题的答案怎么可能是C？
Sir, this cannot become a compound.
这不能变成化合物
The octet rule will break here.
不符合八隅体规则
Yes. You are absolutely correct.
是的，你完全正确
So? - This is an exception, son.
- 所以呢?-这是个例外，孩子
Exception?
例外？
But, sir, rules cannot break in science.
但是，先生，科学不能打破规则
Who told you that?
谁告诉你的？
Exception is the rule of chemistry.
例外是化学的规律
Got it?
明白了吗？
Come on. Let's start salt analysis. Sit down. Sit down.
来吧，我们开始分析盐，坐下吧
Sit down.
坐下
Okay, so. Pay attention. Everybody listen.
好了，注意了，大家都听着
It's very important.
这很重要
Why are you laughing? You got three answers correct.
你笑什么? 你只答对了三道题
You got two. Puffs.
你才对两个，请客吧
We took this very lightly, bro.
我们都答的很认真
Thought it's a piece of cake . It isn't. - Yes, bro. It's certainly not a piece of cake.
我还以为这是小菜一碟，但其实不是 -是的，兄弟，这当然不是小菜一碟
It is extremely spicy today, bro.
今天特别辣
Water.
水
Brother. Water.
兄弟，水
Here. Have this.
给，吃这个吧
Hold this.
拿着这个
Easy. Easy.
放松放松
Okay?
好吗？
May I have it all? - You may.
可以都给我吗?-可以
Just give me the wrapper. - Thank you.
把包装纸给我就好 -谢谢
Wrapper?
包装纸？
He must be eco-friendly.
他一定是个环保主义者
Very promising.
非常有前途
No, no. These are not wrappers. They are my trophies.
不，不，这不是普通的包装纸，是我的奖杯
My fourth chocolate problem.
我解决的第四个奖励题
You can solve the chocolate problem?
你能解决奖励题吗？
You are in A6, aren't you? - So?
你在 A6，是吗?-那又怎样？
Not just me. Five others have also done it.
不仅仅是我，还有其他五个同学也做到了
What are you saying? - Exactly, don't do it. It is only for the A1 batch.
你说什么? -没错，跳过这题，这是给A1学生出的
Give me the wrapper.
把包装纸给我
Bro.
兄弟
So, how much.. Not that it matters to me.
你多少……我不是很在意的哈
How much do you score in Inorganic DPP?
你在无机DPP考试中得了多少分？
In inorganic?
无机物？
About 12 or 13.
12、13分吧
You?
你呢？
13 or 14 types.
13、14分那样子
Yes. 13 or 14.
是的，13、14分
Very promising! Very promising!
非常有前途! 非常有前途！
These people can solve the chocolate problem.
他们可以解决奖励题
What is different in their A6 from our A5?
A6和我们A5有什么不同？
The color of the walls. The width of the benches.
墙壁的颜色，长凳的宽度
The number of fans.
粉丝的数量
Also, the faculty.
还有教职员工
Why?
怎么了？
Come. I'll tell you.
来吧，我知道了
Come. Come. Come.
来来来
What are you doing? Are you insane?
你在干什么? 你疯了吗？
Give him zero. Zero.
给他零分，零分
If Batla's teaching isn't up to the mark..
如果巴特拉的教学不合格
..what will we give him in the feedback form?
我们会给他什么样的反馈？
We will give him a zero, won't we?
给他零分，对吧？
Awarding bad marks and humiliating thereafter suits teachers, not students.
判低分和羞辱学生是老师的事情，而不是学生
That too from A5.
这也是来自A5的
You dork! If we don't give bad feedback..
你这个笨蛋! 如果我们不给出糟糕的反馈
..he only will continue to teach.
他只会继续教下去
Then how will you learn inorganic?
那你怎么学无机物呢？
Teachers are equal to parents.
老师和家长是平等的
Then you should give them feedback too.
那么你也应该给他们反馈
Dad, you are not up to the mark as a father.
爸爸，你不是一个称职的父亲
Hereafter uncle will sleep in your bedroom.
以后隔壁王叔叔睡在你的卧室里
That doesn't make sense. Cool down.
没道理的，冷静点
Go and switch on the fan.
去把风扇打开
The fan won't be switched on today.
风扇今天不开了
But I am feeling a little hot.
但是我觉得有点热
Fill the form first. Then the fan will be switched on.
先填反馈表，然后打开风扇
I am going to drink water.
我要去喝水
Meena!
米纳！
There was this 'Dwapar' era..
这是一个领先的时代
..when Gurus like Dronacharya used to be respected.
像德罗纳查里亚这样的大师在过去备受尊敬
And here is this era.. - Hey! Even Arjun fought Dronacharya.
这就是这个时代……-嘿! 就连阿俊都和德罗纳查里亚打过仗
Even your Ramayana is weak..
你连《罗摩衍那》都没学好
..where as Dronacharya sir was like the best teacher ever.
德罗纳查里亚先生是有史以来最好的老师
Bestest teacher ever!
史上最好的老师！
And yet he fought with him. Why?
但他还是和他打了起来，为什么？
For seizure of a plot.
逮捕阴谋
And you, Meena, can't even fill a single feedback form against Batla for JEE.
而你甚至不能在反馈表上给巴特拉老师打低分
If it were me, I'd have leapt from here.
如果是我，我会从这里跳下去
Go ahead. Give him bad marks. I won't do it.
你自己给他低分吧，我不干
Okay.
好吧
Okay. Fine. Fine.
好吧，好吧
You'll also rot in some private engineering college like that Batla of yours.
你也会像巴特拉一样，烂在一些私立工程学院里
Bloody non-IITians.
考不上印度理工的渣渣
Hey!
嘿！
What's going on? - Nothing, aunty.
怎么了?-没什么，阿姨
I felt a spray of water.
水洒出来了
You are playing holi with drinking water?
你们用饮用水过泼水节呢？
You are right, aunt. - No, aunty. We were simply.
是的，姨妈 -不，阿姨我们只是……
300 rupees will be increased.
罚款300
Aunty. Aunty. - Bunty!
阿姨，阿姨-邦蒂！
Aunty, listen to me. Aunty!
阿姨你听我说，阿姨！
I am just like your Bunty.
我就像你儿子邦迪……
Mummy!
妈！
I will fill water from the neighboring institute.
我以后去旁边的研究所取水
But will not pay this witch! Bloody grouch.
我才不会付钱给这个老巫婆! 该死的
Take this. I've signed it.
拿着，我已经签了名
Fill what you want in it. Son of a witch!
你想怎么写就怎么写吧，混蛋！
Sorry, pal. - It's okay, bro.
对不起 -没关系，兄弟
'Only a cloud understands the thirst of the Earth.'
“只有云才能理解大地的渴望”
Hey, Kumar Vishwas! Come. - Where?
嘿，库马尔维什瓦斯! 来-去哪里？
Come along.
来吧
We have given it..
我们已经给了零分
..but Batla will only be removed when everyone gives bad feedback.
但是只有当每个人都他打零分时，巴特拉才会被解职
"What good is a life with no friends?"
“没有朋友的生活有什么意义? ”
Take this, bro. I filled the form.
拿着，兄弟，我填好了
Remove that scoundrel Chauhan!
赶走那个恶棍肖汉！
The faculty's name is Batla.
教员的名字是巴特拉
Chauhan sir teaches in A2, not in A5.
肖汉先生是A2的老师，不是 A5
Oh crap! I've fallen till A5?
哦，糟糕! 我掉到 A5了？
"Not by maps, not by religion or by need."
“不是根据地图，不是根据宗教或需求”
"My world is made up of friends."
“我的世界是由朋友组成的”
"Made up of your love, your sound and your worship."
“由你的爱，你的声音和你的崇拜组成”
Just a minute.
等一下
No. Neither will I give a negative feedback and nor will let you give it.
不，我不会给出负面的反馈，也不会让你给出负面的反馈
Why? Is he your uncle? - Yes!
为什么? 他是你叔叔吗?-是的！
He is your uncle? - Yes.
他是你叔叔?-是的
Family? - Yes. Family.
家人?-是的，家人
Look, bro. Teaching style.. Batla? - Zero.
兄弟，教学风格……巴特拉? -零分
Two. Two. Let's give the poor chap two.
两分吧，给这个可怜的家伙打个两分
Doubt solving. - Zero!
解答能力 -零！
One. One. One.
一分，一分
Personality. - Zero!
个性 -零！
Zero. Zero. Zero.
零，零，零
And punctuality. - Nil.
还有守时-零
Sorry. I revise my periodic table once daily before lunch and after dinner.
对不起，我每天午饭前和晚饭后都要背诵一次元素周期表
That's nice.
很好
Very nice!
非常好！
The form? - Oh, feedback form!
表格?-哦，反馈表格！
I am doing well in Inorganic so, no need for me to fill it up.
我在无机化学课上学得很好，所以不需要填表了
Well, bye. I have to revise all the atomic radii too.
再见，我还要复习所有的原子半径
Let's go, Vaibhav. Come.
我们走，瓦巴夫，来吧
We are in A5 but we are not destined..
我们在 A5，但我们不是命中注定
..to be able to solve the chocolate problem like the A6 students.
能像 A6的学生一样解决奖励题
What did you say?
你说什么？
Very nice initiative!
非常好的主动性！
Batla should be changed.
巴特拉应该换了
In fact, every teacher in this coaching class should be changed.
事实上，这个培训班的每一位老师都应该换掉
No, no. This coaching industry should change.
不，不，这个行业应该改变
Exam pattern, syllabus, curriculum. Pedagogy should change.
考试模式、教学大纲、课程设置
IIT should change. This whole educational system should change.
理工学院应该改，整个教育体系都应该改
And for that..
为此……
..patriarchy should change.
应该改变父权制
What do you think, Shivangi?
你觉得怎么样，施万吉？
I think you should attend class first.
我认为你应该先上课
A1, A2, A3, A4, A5. Inorganic.
A1，A2，A3，A4，A5.
What is AWS under inorganic?
无机物下的 AWS 是什么？
Awasthi. Will he teach us now? - What? Batla is gone?
阿瓦斯，以后他教我们吗?-什么? 巴特拉走了？
He acted very respectable.
他走得很体面
He isn't gone. He has been removed.
他不是离开的，而是被离开的
Uncle.
叔叔
Mr. Batla. - Hi.
巴特拉先生-你好
How are you? - Yes. Sit. Sit. Sit.
你好 -好，坐，坐，坐
So, tell me. What brings you here?
什么风把你吹来了？
I just wanted to talk to you, sir.
我只是想和你谈谈，先生
Yes, yes. Tell me. - Sir, I've lost A5.
嗯，你说吧-先生，我不能继续在A5授课了
Yes. - If you could let me give extra classes to resolve doubts..
是的-如果您能让我上额外的课来解决疑问的话……
Doubt classes that too of Inorganic? Who will attend, sir?
对无机化学课程也有疑问吗? 谁会来上课，先生？
Just don't decrease my salary. I will do anything.
只要不降低我的工资，我什么都愿意做
Give me a junior class if you wish.
给我一个低年级的班
I can even teach 8th grade physics.
我还可以教八年级的物理
How can you say that, sir? You are respectable to us, sir.
你怎么能这么说? 我们都很尊敬你
Not true, sir. The other subjects are respected..
不是这样的，先生，当无机化学需要刻苦学习时
..when inorganic demands the most hard work. - Yes.
其他学科才会收到尊重-是的
One has to revise every morning.
每天早上都要复习
Yet the others have better salaries.
然而其他人的工资更高
Look, sir. Math and Physics are taught by IITians.
听着，先生，数学和物理老师都是理工学院毕业的
Pay less to them and other institutes poach them.
如果给他们钱少了一定会跳槽的
That's why brother-in-law pays them so much.
这就是姐夫付给他们高薪的原因
What can I do in this matter, sir?
我又能怎么样呢，先生？
I could only offer your nephew a scholarship. Did I or didn't I?
我只能给你侄子提供奖学金，对不对？
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
When in fact, he didn't deserve it.
事实上，他并没有得奖学金的资格
But, sir, even if I was to be removed Mr. Rao. would've been a respectable replacement.
但就算是要换掉我，饶先生也是个不错的替代者
Or maybe that teacher of A6. Parminder.
或者是 A6的老师帕敏德
Even he would have been a better option.
即使是他也会是一个更好的选择
But sir, you replaced me with my junior.
但是，你却用我的下属代替了我
You know what, sir? He is a psycho.
他就是个神经病
He doesn't know anything. He used to attend my lectures.
他什么都不懂，还经常来听我的课
In that case, sir, even you made a mistake, didn't you?
那样的话，你自己也有问题，不是吗？
Junior and senior don't matter in inorganic, sir.
初级和高级在无机化学里无关紧要
Someone had to be retained. So, we did.
总得有人留下，所以我们就留下了他
And that poor chap will be a psycho.
那个可怜的家伙肯定是个神经病
He too has been idling at home for the past 4 months.
在过去的四个月里，他也一直在家里无所事事
He can idle another four months. He owns two hostels.
他还能再空闲四个月，他有两家旅馆
Tell me something, sir. If he was a true teacher..
告诉我，先生，如果他是一个真正的老师
..wouldn't he join some coaching institute by now?
他现在不是应该加入什么教师学院了吗？
Why are you making fun of the poor chap, sir?
你为什么要取笑这个可怜的家伙，先生？
Even you are aware no institute poaches Inorganic faculty.
就连你都知道，没有一所学院会挖角化学老师
Up! Stand up quickly!
站起来! 快点站起来！
What have you studied till date if you don't know this exception?
如果你不知道这个例外情况，那么到今天为止你都学了什么？
Call your family today and tell them you won't be able to crack IIT.
今天打电话给你的父母，告诉他们你考不上印度理工
And if you don't have the courage to tell them, then download 'tic tok'.
如果你没有勇气告诉他们，那就下载个抖音
Many jerks like you dance there and even earn more than they deserve.
许多像你这样的混蛋在那里面跳舞，甚至赚得还不少
I'll be your first customer. Take this!
我第一个给你点赞
You scored four out of fifteen.
15道题才得4分
Sir, do you discuss the chocolate problems? - Yes, yes.
先生，你们讲解过后面的超纲题吗?-是的
Of course I do. - So what is the reason for this exception...
我当然知道-那么这个题例外的原因是什么
But only with A1 batch students.
但我只和A1的学生讨论
..because they don't ask stupid questions like A5 students.
因为他们不会像A5学生那样问愚蠢的问题
These are facts, information. But no!
"这些都是事实，但是不行"
"We want logic."
“我们需要逻辑”
Sir, why do notes only come in 100 and 50 rupee denominations?
"先生，为什么纸币只有100和50卢比的面额？"
Why not 75?
"为什么没有75？"
Why did Ranbir choose Alia? Why not Deepika?
"为什么兰比尔选择了阿莉亚? 为什么不是迪皮卡？"
Simply memorize what's written and be done with it.
你只要记住就可以了
But no! "We want logic. We want to be toppers."
但是不行! “我们要逻辑，我们要成为顶级人物”
"Sir, do you know why I am a topper from A5 and not from A1?
“先生，你知道为什么我是 A5而不是 A1的吗？
Because I am an ass."
因为我是蠢驴”
Hee-haw! Hee-haw! Hee-haw!
咿哈! 咿哈! 咿哈！
If you want to learn inorganic then you do as I tell you.
如果你想学好无机化学，那就照我说的做
Keep memorizing it. That's that!
继续背，就这样！
No questions asked.
毫无疑问
Everyone got it!? - Yes, sir!
大家都明白了吗?-是的，长官！
Say it aloud. - Yes, sir!
大声说出来-是，长官！
I can't hear you. - Yes, sir!
我听不见-是，长官！
Good!
很好！
Now some questions from JEE '97.
现在我们来看一些97年的真题
We shall solve them.
我们可以解出来的
They're really important for you guys.
这题对你们来说真的很重要
Remove your note books.
打开你的笔记本
Sir, we have a request.
先生，我们有个请求
Have you paid the installment? - We paid it, sir!
你付分期付款了吗?-我们付了，先生！
We paid it long ago.
我们很久以前就付清了
Okay, talk.
好吧说吧
Sir, you..
先生，你..
Sir, can the Inorganic faculty be changed once again?
先生，化学老师还能换人吗？
Yes.
可以
Why not?
为什么不呢？
Fill the feedback form next year.
明年填写反馈表
It'll be changed.
就可以换了
Sir. Next year will be too late, sir.
先生，明年就太晚了，先生
Why don't you reinstate Batla sir?
你为什么不让巴特拉复职呢，先生？
You worthless chaps should never be given the feedback forms.
你们这些没用的家伙就不配填反馈表
The toppers never make any fuss.
顶尖的学生都没大惊小怪
Get out!
出去！
They want to be IITians.
就这还想考印度理工
Meenal is also frustrated, sir.
米纳尔也很沮丧，先生
What happened to her? - Hee-haw. Hee-haw.
她怎么了
Call Meenal.
给她打电话
You idiot! Give it to me!
你这个白痴! 给我！
I've told you so many times you should know topper's phone numbers by heart.
我告诉过你很多次了，你要把这个号码牢记在心
Hello. Oh sweet child Meenal.
你好哦，可爱的孩子米纳尔
(sobs)
(哭泣)
Is there any... problem with the new sir?
新来的化学老师有什么问题吗？
Tell me, child.
告诉我，孩子
Yes, sir. A little bit.
是的，先生，有一点
Then why did you wait? You are this year's topper.
那你还等什么? 你是今年的头牌
Topper?
头牌？
- Girls topper.
- 女生头牌
If anything happens, you should message me immediately.
如果有什么事，你应该立即给我发信息
That's why you have my personal number.
所以你才有我的私人电话
Yes, sir. I changed my phone so, your number got misplaced.
是的，先生我换了手机，所以你的号码弄丢了
Take it down.
来，记好
9-8-6-2...
9862...
I'll give it to you later.
我一会儿给你
Okay.
好吧
Put Awasthi in the foundation course.
把阿瓦斯换到基础班
Tell me. Which sir would you like?
告诉我，你想要哪个先生？
The teacher from A6.
来自 A6的老师
Yes. The teacher from A6.
是的，A6的老师
Par...min...der.
帕... 米... 德
Okay - Yes.
好的-好的
Okay.
好吧
Look. She is this dude's girlfriend..
听着，她是这家伙的女朋友
..but who all are chasing her? All the boys in Kota?
但是谁在追她? 所有科塔的男孩？
The boys from where? - Boys in Kota!
哪里来的男孩?-科塔的男孩！
But dude's girlfriend refuses everyone except 'the dude'.
但是这家伙的女朋友拒绝了所有人，除了“这家伙”
So what does that make the dude? - Exception.
那这家伙算什么?-例外
And what does that make the girlfriend?
那他的女朋友是什么？
Innocent. She fell for that jerk!
无辜的，她爱上那个混蛋了！
We must understand the gist of the matter.
我们必须了解这件事的要点
Anywhere there is chemistry, there is? - Exception!
任何有化学反应的地方都有什么?-例外！
Very good! This is fun.
非常好! 这很有趣
So the dude sees me outside the class and says Inorganic chemistry is dangerous.
所以那家伙在课堂外看到我，说无机化学是危险的
It is very complicated.
这非常复杂
I will quit.
我不干了
I said, brother, your girlfriend is also complicated.
我说，兄弟，你的女朋友也很复杂
Do you leave her?
你会离开她吗？
No. What do you do with her? You pay her attention.
- 不会，你要怎么做?-你会时刻关注她
You focus on her. You talk to her nicely.
你把注意力集中在她身上，好好跟她说话
Shona. Mona. Babu. Jadu. Tona.
肖纳，莫娜，巴布，杰杜，托纳
What else do you call?
还会叫什么？
Look at that. On hearing it even the Bajrang dal at the back is attentive.
看看，这个听到这个，连坐在后排听课的教师都很专注
Hello. Sit straight.
你好，坐直了
Yes.
是的
You find it very amusing, bro.
你觉得这很有趣，兄弟
Stand up.
站起来
You have a girlfriend?
你有女朋友吗？
You don't. That's not surprising.
你没有，情理之中
Sit down.
坐下
Just as our brother here is alone, similarly boron is alone.
正如这位小老弟是孤独的，同样，硼也是孤独的
Boron is short of electrons but nobody is giving it.
硼缺少电子，但是没有人给它
So, what will we do?
那么，我们该怎么办？
Will it remain alone?
它会继续独自存在吗？
Is our brother sitting alone? No.
- 我们的兄弟一个人坐着吗?-不
Brother found a monkey just like him.
哥哥发现一只和他一模一样的猴子
What did he find? - Monkey!
他发现了什么?-猴子！
Friend. Only I will say monkey.
朋友，只有我会说猴子
So the boron finds boron like itself..
所以硼和自己是一样的
..and forms a bond with it.
并与之形成一种联系
Not James Bond. Bond.
不是詹姆斯 · 邦德，是连接
When two friends make a bond what is it called?
当两个朋友结合在一起，这叫什么？
It will become a banana, sir.
它会变成一根香蕉，先生
Very good answer!
非常好的回答！
It will form a banana bond.
它会形成一个香蕉键
The educated people call it three-center to two electron bond.
学者们称之为三中心到两个电子键
What is it called? - Three-center to two electron bond!
它叫什么?-三个中心对两个电子键！
No need to remember that. It will not help you clear IIT.
不需要记住这个，它不会帮助走进印度理工
What do we want to clear? - IIT!
我们的目标是什么?-印度理工
Very good!
非常好！
So you two. Have you formed a bond?
那么你们两个，你们有联系吗？
Have you formed a bond?
你们之间有联系吗？
Come on. Write in your book.
来吧，写在你的书上
When two atoms combine to form a bond of similar type..
当两个原子结合形成类似的键时
..due to lack of electrons, the bond is known as banana bond.
由于缺乏电子，这种键被称为香蕉键
Children, if there is any question on banana bond, we will do it?
孩子们，如果有任何关于香蕉键的问题，我们会做吗？
Yes, sir!
会！
That means banana bond? - Is not a problem.
也就是说香蕉键?-没问题
The bell has rung.
铃声已经响了
Everyone will complete their sheets and bring them in tomorrow.
回去记得做作业，明天再交上来
Those who don't complete it will get a punch from me. Okay?
那些没有完成的人会挨我一拳，好吗？
Bye. - Sir! Sir! Sir! Let's have a song.
- 再见-先生! 先生! 先生! 我们来唱首歌吧
A song, sir.
一首歌，先生
Yes, sir. A song, sir.
是的，先生，一首歌，先生
Please, sir. Please, sir. Please, sir. Please, sir.
求你了，先生求你了……
Silence!
安静！
Are you here to listen to songs? I sing songs?
你是来听歌的吗? 让我唱歌？
Is this 'Indian Idol'?
这是《印度偶像》吗？
Is this why your parents pay your fees?
你们父母花钱送你来是听歌的吗？
Sing a song, sir. Sing a song.
还让我唱首歌……
He explains so well. He made it so easy.
他解释得很清楚，很简单
Apart from being the best teacher he is the best singer also.
不仅是个好老师，也是个不错的歌手
The boys from A6 said so.
A6的同学都是这么说的
But they never said he makes you laugh so much too. - That's right.
但是他们从来没有说过他还很幽默-没错
I swear if he wasn't a teacher he would surely do stand up comedy.
我发誓，如果他不是老师，一定能上脱口秀大会
Praise the lord. Its like we got the 'Jeetu Bhaiya' of Inorganic chemistry. - Yes.
太好了，我们得到了无机化学的杰图·拜亚-是的
I remember the whole lecture vividly.
我清楚地记得整堂课
I won't have to refer to my notes to do the DPP.
我不需要参考我的笔记就能完成DPP
It's nice. He teaches us while singing. That's how the class should be.
真不错，他一边教我们唱歌，这才是课堂应该有的样子
Today my brain has opened to chemistry.
今天，我的大脑开始产生化学反应
It's already open. - It has opened today.
门已经开了 -我今天开悟了
The door is already open.
我说门已经开了
Clean all the cobwebs from here.
把这里的蜘蛛网清理干净
Move the suitcases and throw away all the garbage.
把箱子挪开，把所有的垃圾都扔掉
Welcome, prince.
少爷回来了
It seems to me I'll have to cut money from your security now.
在我看来，我要从你的押金里面扣除一些卫生费了
What happened now, aunty? - What is this?
这又是怎么了，阿姨?-这是什么？
The floor.
地板
What is on the floor? - You.
地板上是什么?-你
You are being a wise ass.
别跟我耍小聪明
What kind of stains are those? Crispy. Crispy.
- 这是什么污渍? -脆皮
Even lizol can't remove these.
即使是蜥蜴也不能去除这些污渍
I am warning you. I am warning you I don't want even a scratch on my Kota marble.
我警告过你，我不想在我的科塔大理石上留下任何痕迹
This is not Kota marble. It is Kota stone.
这不是科塔的大理石，这是科塔的石头
What did you say to my face?
你再说一遍？
Aunty, hereafter we shall take more care of your marble than our books.
阿姨，以后我们对你的大理石要比对我们的书更加小心
Oh, no.
哦，不
Hereafter we will have daily cleaning here..
以后我们每天都要打扫这里
..and you will have to pay 500 rupees per month for it.
你每个月要付500卢比
Let's go.
我们走
Hey! - Get out of my way. You don't even shower.
嘿!-让开，你甚至都没洗澡
'Aunty, give me hot water.'
阿姨，您这也没热水啊
Filthy rascals.
肮脏的流氓
I wish I had a feedback form for this Tarka as well.
我希望我能有这个阿姨的反馈表
Never mind Supankha. You are a hero.
别管这个了，你现在是个英雄
If it hadn't been for you neither would the inorganic teacher change..
如果不是因为你，化学老师也不能换
..nor would my luck.
我的运气也不会
Brother, I will give you my first two chocolates as offerings.
兄弟，我会把我的前两个超纲起奖励作为供品给你
Its alright, junior.
别客气，老弟
Come on, children. Remove your sheets. We shall begin now.
来吧，孩子们，把你们的试卷打开，我们现在开始
I will tell you the answers. Check your answers.
对答案
The first. Very easy question. It's a shame to even discuss it.
第一题，非常简单的问题，说都不想说了
The answer is A. Mark it and move on. Tally it.
答案是A，记好了，然后继续下一题
Tell me the second. B. ZnS.
第二题选B
Which of you have done the third? It is a very easy question.
你们谁做过第三题？ 这是一个非常简单的问题
We shall solve it orally. Its a shame if you use your pens.
这题口算就能解决，你要是用笔算那就太不应该了
The answer is B.
答案是B
What is this? Such easy questions. Time waste.
这是什么? 这么简单的问题简直浪费时间
Even more basic question. C is the answer.
非常基础的问题，答案是C
If you got this wrong, get yourself checked.
如果你做错了，好好检查一下自己吧
Question number 4.
第四题
The answer is B. Very basic.
答案是B，非常基础
The answer is C. I did it in the last class.
答案是C 我上节课讲过
You should have no problem.
你们应该没问题
Sixth question. Let's go to the eighth question. - Sir!
第六个问题，让我们回到第八个问题-先生！
Sir. How can the answer to question 7 be A? - Son, that..
先生，第七题的答案怎么可能是A?-孩子，那个……
It should be C, shouldn't it? - Let's complete this and then I will..
它应该是C，不是吗? -我们先对答案，等下我再讲解
No, no, sir. Tell me this first.
不，不，先生，先告诉我
Sir, aluminum is from the boron family.
先生，铝是硼家族的
It doesn't have electrons either.
它也没有电子
So, it will form a bond with another one like itself.
因此，它会和另一个类似它自己的物质形成一种联系
So it will make a banana bond.
所以它会形成一个香蕉键
What is this coordinate covenant bond?
这个并列的契约是什么？
That is the exception, son. I taught you that in class.
这是个例外，孩子，我在课堂上教过你
But, sir, the banana bond is an exception in itself.
但是，先生，香蕉键本身就是一个例外
Son, this is an exception to the exception.
孩子，这是个例外
Class, what did I say was the first rule of chemistry?
同学们，我说过化学的第一法则是什么？
Anywhere there is chemistry, there is? - Exception!
任何有化学反应的地方都有什么?-例外！
Let's move on.
我们继续
The eighth question. D.
第八题
Don't take stress. We will solve the chocolate problem.
别紧张，我们会解决超纲题的
Hey, bro! What's up? - Scram!
嘿，兄弟! 怎么了?-滚开！
Scram! Scram! - Go.
滚！ 滚！-快走
Is he crazy?
他疯了吗？
Meena, get out of this illusion.
米纳，别再幻想了
We are not going to get chocolate.
我们不会解开奖励题的
Do you understand? We won't be able to do anything.
你明白吗? 我们什么也做不了
We won't be able to do anything no matter how many teachers are changed.
不管换多少老师，我们也做不了什么
I made enquiries.
我打听了一下
The A6 batch students have also taken a corresponddence course of our institute.
这批 A6级的学生也参加了我们学院的相关课程
The scoundrels have the solutions before the DPP is discussed.
在做dpp之前，他们就已经学过了
They get chocolate but they don't score marks in the test.
他们有巧克力，但是他们在考试中没有得分
That's why they are still in A6.
这就是他们仍然在A6的原因
Why don't we take private classes outside the institute for inorganic.
我们为什么不去找个化学私教呢
Really? - Yes.
- 真的?-是的
And what will we gain from it?
那又能怎样呢？
What will we gain from it? What will we gain?
找私教又能怎样？
They will teach us well, won't they? Even these people are teaching us well.
能帮我们提高成绩，不是吗?
Meena, the problem is not with the teachers.
米纳，问题不在于老师
The problem is with this nasty subject!
问题在于这个讨厌的学科！
It is an utterly boring subject!
这是一个无聊透顶的学科！
There are only facts that have no logic.
没有任何逻辑可言
There are more exceptions than the number of rules in the name of logic.
在逻辑的名义下，例外比规则多得多
In the first octet rule they say there should be only 8 electrons..
在第一个八隅律中，他们说应该只有8个电子
..but then any number of electrons are making compounds.
但是任何数量的电子都会产生化合物
Four. Six. Seven. Eight. Ten.
四，六，七，八，十
And Twelve. - Yes.
- 十二个-是的
One atom has so many models.
一个原子有这么多模型
First they teach you Dalton's model.
首先他们教你道尔顿的模型
The moment you understand it they say, "Oh, this is incorrect."
当你明白的时候，他们会说，“哦，这是不正确的”
Alright. Let's say they made a mistake once.
好吧，假设他们犯了一次错误
Then they teach you Thompson plum pudding model. Even that is wrong.
然后他们教你汤普森梅子布丁模型，即使这是错误的
Then they teach you Rutherford model. Even that is incorrect.
然后他们教你卢瑟福模型，然而这也是不正确的
Then why are you teaching us?
那你为什么要教我们？
Make it first. Sit down and make it.
坐下来，别急
No, no, no. We will teach you.
我们会教你的
We will teach you. Bohr's model.
我们会教你波尔的模型
Heisenberg model.
海森堡模型
None of them are entirely correct.
没有一个是完全正确的
These people are making fools of us by calling it exception.
他们说这是例外，完全是在愚弄我们
This is not an exception. It is an excuse. Pure excuse.
这不是例外，而是借口，纯粹的借口
They don't have a theory that gives you all the answers.
他们并没有给出解题的理论依据
And how could they have a theory? Tell me. How could they have it?
他们怎么会有理论? 告诉我，他们怎么会有理论？
Geniuses like Einstein and Newton gave theories.
像爱因斯坦和牛顿这样的天才提出了理论
They never read this moronic subject.
他们从不学这种低能的学科
There's no logic.
这没有逻辑
All they have is exception, exception and exception.
他们只有例外，和更多的例外
'Inception' did not confuse me as much as exception has.
《盗梦空间》并没有像这些意外那样让我感到困惑
Every atom acts and reacts as it pleases here.
在这里，每个原子都可以随心所欲地行动和反应
The oxidation state of all of them changes.
它们的氧化状态都发生了变化
Plus two. Minus seven. Plus three. Minus half.
加二减七加三减一半
Even the oxidation state of oxygen is not fixed.
即使氧的氧化状态也是不固定的
When your own elements don't give a damn..
当你自己的元素不在乎的时候
..then why make a happy periodic family? Why?
那为什么要组建一个幸福的周期性家庭? 为什么？
Learn from math. Learn.
学学人家数学
Zero to nine is fixed once and for all. Final.
零到九是固定的
But here, their elements aren't fixed till date.
但在化学，元素直到现在都是不固定的。
Something new crops up every year.
每年都有新的元素出现
Boom! Number 113 is the number picked in this year's lucky draw.
砰! 113号是今年抽奖的号码
We shall call it! Nikenugium. No, no, no. Nikeniugium!
我们就把它叫做'锹'好了
Damn it! It is easier to recite a Sanskrit mantra.
该死! 背诵梵文咒语都比这容易
Newton gave us three laws. Three.
牛顿给了我们三个定律，三个
Half our physics is covered with it..
我们物理学的一半都被它覆盖了
..but here, there is a new rule for every question.
但在这里，每个问题都有一个新规则
Admit it. Admit that you are not logical like physics and math.
承认吧，承认你不像物理和数学那样有逻辑
Okay. Eat some.. - No!
好吧，吃点...-不！
Tell me something. It is simple.
告诉我，这很简单
What will happen if you toss an apple in the air?
如果你把苹果抛向空中会发生什么？
It will fall. - It will fall? It will fall?
它会掉下来-它会掉下来? 对吧？
But it will fall in physics. It won't fall in chemistry.
物理学上它会掉下来，但是化学上并不会
What will happen in chemistry? There will be steric hindrance.
化学中会发生什么? 会有空间位阻
If that's not enough then resonance, inductive effect.
如果这还不够，那么共鸣，诱导效应
Everything will happen. Anything can happen here.
一切都会发生，任何事都可能发生
They don't even name the colors simply.
他们甚至不会简单地命名颜色
It's not green. It's apple green. It's not red. It's crimson red.
绿色不叫绿色，叫苹果绿，红色不叫红色，叫深红色
It's not pink. It's hot pink!
粉红不叫粉红，叫桃红！
That's why only girls are so good at chemistry.
这就是为什么只有女孩子才会这么擅长化学
They make you do nonsense.
还会让你做无厘头的事情
Flame test. Salt analysis. Titration. Brown ring test.
火焰试验. 盐分析. 滴定. 布朗环试验
Rotten eggs smell. Why should I smell a rotten egg?
还有臭鸡蛋的味道，为什么我要闻到臭鸡蛋的味道？
Why? I am a Brahmin!
为什么? 我是个婆罗门（吃素）！
Atomic size trend. Ionization potential trend.
原子大小趋势电离势趋势
Electron-affinity trend. Electron -negativity trend. Horizontal trend.
电子亲和力趋势，电子负性趋势，水平趋势
Vertical trend.
纵向趋势
You can call something a trend when you can predict something with it.
当你可以预测某事时，你可以把它称为一种趋势
If anything is happening anywhere and anytime like 'Thugs of Hindustan'..
如果任何时间任何地点发生任何事情，就像“印度斯坦的暴徒”一样
..then how can they call it a trend?
那他们怎么能称之为趋势呢？
How can they call it that?
他们怎么能这么说？
I am telling you, Meena.
我告诉你，米纳
Chemistry is not a subject. It is subjective.
化学不是一门学科，它是主观的
I did so much for this subject.
我为这个学科付出了很多
Assignments, notes, flash cards. I sat in the front row.
作业，笔记，卡片，我坐在前排
Changed three teachers. Changed the studying strategy.
换了三个老师，换了学习策略
But what is the end result? Zilch!
但最终的结果是什么呢? 一无所获！
He wouldn't stop, Jeetu Bhaiya.
他停不下来了，拜亚哥
That's why I brought him to you.
所以我才带他来见你
You have understood it correctly.
你的理解是正确的
The problem is not with the teacher, it's with the subject.
问题不在于老师，而在于学科
There must be some reason you find physicists only in universities..
你只能在大学里找到物理学家一定是有原因的
..while you find chemists at every corner.
而你在每个角落都能找到药剂师
You understand that you cannot memorize so much, right?
你知道你不能背那么多东西，对吧？
Fine. - But how does that solve the problem, Bhaiya?
好吧-但是这个问题要怎么解决呢，拜亚哥
It isn't? - No.
你不知道吗？-不知道
I thought it was simple.
我认为这很简单
Okay, let's say you have to go on a date.
好吧，假设你要去约会
You have a girlfriend? - No.
你有女朋友吗?-没有
Let's assume you have a hot girl like Katrina.
假设你有一个像卡特里娜这样的性感女友
Ma'am is punctual. She calls you at 8 o'clock sharp.
她很准时，八点整打电话给你
If you're going on a date you will take a gift for her, won't you?
如果你要去约会，你会带一份礼物给她，是吗？
Champagne, bouquet.. - Teddy bear. Pink.
香槟，花束 -还有粉红的泰迪玩偶
Your ideas are very different.
你的想法非常不同
Anyway, let's assume you take a teddy bear.
无论如何，让我们假设你拿了一个玩偶
You bump into a thief on the way.
你在路上碰到一个小偷
He snatches the teddy bear and runs.
他抓起玩偶就跑了
What will you do? - How can he run away?
你会怎么做?-他怎么能逃跑呢？
I will catch hold of him and punch him.
我要抓住他，揍他一顿
Of course. Ideally that's what you should do.
当然，理想情况下你应该这么做
But the thief is fast.
但是小偷很快
And you have two gifts in your hands. Then?
现在你手里还有两份礼物，然后呢？
Then we scream aloud. Someone will surely help.
然后我们大声尖叫，肯定会有人来帮忙的
That could be one approach.
这可能是一种方法
Maybe it will work. What will you do?
也许会成功，你会怎么做？
I will forget about the gift..
我会忘记这个玩偶
..and rush with the remaining two gifts.
然后带着剩下的两个礼物冲过去
So, rush!
所以，赶快！
I told you it is simple. IIT is the hot gal.
我告诉过你这很简单，印度理工是个性感的女孩
Sure. The bouquet and champagne are math and physics..
当然花束和香槟是数学和物理
..while the teddy is inorganic chemistry..
. . 而泰迪熊就是
..which we are unable to get hold of.
我们学不会的化学
But, Bhaiya, the real life girlfriend wants the teddy.
但是，拜亚哥，现实生活中的女朋友就是想要泰迪熊
I won't get admission into IIT without inorganic.
不学化学我就考不上印度理工学院
Who says so?
谁说的？
Who is the IITian in this room?
你们还有谁是印度理工毕业的吗？
Do you think I memorized chemistry like a jackass?
你以为我会像傻瓜一样背化学吗？
Before you study for an exam, study the exam.
在你准备考试之前，先学习考试
What do you think? How much do you need to score during those six hours to get into top five IITs?
你觉得怎么样？在这六个小时里，你需要得多少分才能考上印度理工？
90 percent for top five.. - No, no. Are you insane? 95 percent.
90%-不，不，你疯了吗? 肯定要95%才行
How will you face this savage world?
你们要如何面对这个野蛮的世界?
It will eat you alive! 40 percent.
它会把你生吞活剥了，40%
Only 40 percent for top five?
只需要40%？
Only 40 percent for top five IIT?
得到40%就能排前五了？
You are kidding, aren't you, Bhaiyar?
你在开玩笑吗，拜亚哥？
There are many things apart from memes on the internet.
互联网上有很多东西
Go and watch videos of Unacademy. Strategy for IIT JEE.
去看看非学术的讲座视频： IIT JEE 的战略
JEE toppers and scientists take time out to make some videos for you.
JEE的出题者和科学家会抽出时间为你制作一些视频
At least do that much. Is your Jeetu Bhaiya going to solve everything?
你拜亚哥我能解决所有问题吗？
Even if omit 60 percent of the syllabus..
即使省略教学大纲的60%
..you still stand a chance to get into IIT.
你还是有机会进入印度理工学院
The syllabus for inorganic chemistry might be vast.
无机化学的教学大纲可能非常庞大
So, let it be.
所以，随它去吧
How much weightage does it carry in our exam?
它在我们的考试中有多重？
How much weightage would chemistry carry in our exam? Tell me.
化学在我们的考试中会占多大比重? 告诉我
Chemistry would be one-third. - 33 percent.
化学是三分之一-33%
One third of that would be.. - 11 percent.
其中三分之一是. .-11%
Think about it.
想想吧
Do you want to chase 11 percent..
你想追求这11% 的分数吗
..and ruin the crease on your trousers..
... 弄皱你刚熨好的裤子
..or focus on 89 percent?
还是专注于89% ？
Score 40 percent and then enjoy in a good IIT for four years.
得分40% ，然后享受在印度理工的四年
Bhaiya, I shall burn up all the sheets of Inorganic today.
拜亚哥，我今天要把所有的无机化学书都烧掉
End of story! - That's wrong.
-就这样!-那样不对
Yes. It is knowledge. It is a sin.
是的，这是知识，烧书是罪恶的
Sell it as waste paper.
把它当废纸卖掉
You will get some money. Eat some snacks with it.
还能换一些钱用它吃零食
But, Jeetu Bhaiya, one can improve one's rank with inorganic, right?
但是，拜亚哥，化学可以提高名次不是吗？
Inorganic improves the rank of those who are actually getting a rank.
化学提高了那些正在获得排名的人的排名
But in your case, it will leave you rankless.
但在你的情况下，它会让你失去排名
So, the best way to tackle problems like these..
所以，解决这些问题的最好方法
..is not to get involved. Just take the fast lane.
就是不要掺和进来
Do you understand? Come on, you guys. Leave. Leave.
你明白吗? 快点，你们这些家伙，走吧
Go.
去吧
Why do you look so confused, Meena?
你为什么看起来这么困惑，米纳？
But, Jeetu Bhaiya, the other day you said..
但是，拜亚哥，那天你说..
..if you have a problem in life you confront it.
如果你在生活中遇到困难，要勇敢面对
Make your problem a dare. Make your dare a habit and forge ahead.
让你的问题成为挑战，让挑战成为习惯，勇往直前
Today you are saying to let Inorganic go if we don't know it.
今天你却说让我们放弃化学
Son, Inorganic chemistry is an exception.
孩子，无机化学是个例外
Come on. Leave.
走吧，走吧
Thank you, Bhaiya.
谢谢你，拜亚哥
Objective in the exams should not be to solve all the problems..
考试的目标不应该是解决所有的问题
..but to solve the maximum number of questions.
而是为了解决最多的问题
If the problem is very confusing and time consuming, they you can skip it.
如果问题是非常困惑和费时的，他们可以跳过它
If you have any time remaining then get back to it.
如果你还有剩余的时间，再回头去看
Bear in mind, not every problem is meant to be solved.
记住，并不是每个问题都是要解决的
Vaibhav Pandey! - Aunty?
瓦伊巴夫潘迪!-阿姨？
I've told you so many times not to put so many clothes..
我告诉过你多少次了，不要扔那么多衣服
..in the second hand washing machine.
在二手洗衣机里
Do you think about electricity and water?
你考虑过水和电吗？
Aunty.
阿姨
How are you?
近来可好？
Take this. This is your extra charge.
拿着这个，这是你的额外费用
And I shall give it to you every month.
我每个月都会给你
Just don't disturb me for the entire month.
麻烦您整个月都不要打扰我
Thank you.
谢谢你